Hi and welcome to a new video on my channel and it's going to be crafting
video because after my time last video of making a latex bodysuit a lot of you
got really specific questions so I thought let's do a mini series about how
to make latex garments in which I'll explain a bit more. Today's first episode
is all about basic equipment, what do you need to start and in the next videos I'm
going to show you step by step how to make latex garments for example a top or leggings
of course you need your latex sheet material i have several yeah colors here from wearflex
they produce the classic sheet latex and i'm happy that i could team up with them for this video
series. So first a pen. I prefer gel liners because you see them on black
latex. You can also use a ball pen for example for transferring your pattern
onto the latex. If you transferred your pattern onto the latex you'll need a
rotary cutter to cut out the latex panels for your garment. Then what you
need is some white spirit to clean the latex and get rid of the talcum that is
on the sheet latex. I just use a cloth for that and from the hardware store
white spirit. For the glue I use vulcanization fluid. I do not use the
white latex milk for normal scenes and I apply it with a brush. That's pretty
basic actually. And if you've done the seam you use this roller to apply pressure onto
the seam so the glue and the sheets stick together.
Alright now that you know what you need to start let's do the first latex seam. For that
I have two small pieces of latex because it'll be enough for now.
As I said I'm going to use my white spirit to clean the latex.
It is completely normal that it starts rolling up here.
You have a front side and a back side because you do put them on top of each other.
So of course you need to put glue on the top from one side and on the back side from the
other so you can like flip it over.
At some point it will start unrolling again and then you'll know that you're good to go.
For my glue I just put it in a small glass jar, don't get confused.
I'll link the materials in the description text down below.
So I'm going to dip in my brush and just apply really a thin layer along the edge of the
latex.
It'll start rolling up again but don't worry, stay relaxed.
That's like the most important tip.
It'll unroll again at some point probably, especially if you're working with thicker
latex.
Just going to apply it on the other sheet.
wait till it's dry. In between I'm going to clean my mat so there's not too much
leftover glue on the mat and wait for it to unroll again. Now I'm going to take
the top layer into my hand and start laying the sheets on top of each other.
I'm not pressing too much in the beginning, just doing it nice and slow
and evenly.
That's it!
It all comes down to practice.
I promise you the more often you're doing this the easier it gets.
So this is my finished seam.
I pressed it a bit together with my fingers but for it to really stick together I'm going
to apply pressure with this roller here.
Done! You could basically wear the garment now if you are done with
applying pressure. So I can pull and it sticks together. You don't need time to
dry it, you don't need to put it on a radiator or whatever. This is good to go.
Just keep your latex out of the sunlight and if you're done with your garment you
can wash it. I do have a video about latex care just click here and I guess
I'll see you in the next video for our first project. See you around, bye!